RENATO GODOIS

CLOUD ARCHITECT

INFORMATION CONTACT:

Phone: + 55 41 99252-6490 Email: renatogodois@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/renatogodois

Curitiba - Brazil

SUMMARY

Cloud Architect with extensive experience and a proven track record of over 15 years of work in the information technology and services industry. Strong technical knowledge on Microsoft products, focused on Windows Platform (Remote Desktop Service, Bitlocker, Windows Server and Client Deployment, Print Server, Microsoft Product Activation, Failover Cluster, Active Directory, Certification Authority ...) and Azure, also strong knowledge on GCP (Google Cloud Platform) environment. I also have experience in Linux environments (Debian and CentOS), configuration of Squid, Samba, LDAP, Backup servers. Knowledge of the ITIL process. Information Technology Professional with MBA and Information Security Management. Microsoft Expert Infrastructure Certified (MCSE), Azure Architect Expert, Azure DevOps Expert, Google Cloud Associate Engineer and Google Cloud Professional Architect

SKILLS

- Windows Server Infrastructure
- Windows Azure
- Azure DevOps
- Google Cloud Platform

LANGUAGES

- English (Professional work)
- Spanish (Professional work)
- French (Basic in progress)
- Portuguese (Native)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

CLOUD ARCHITECT

GFT, Mar 2021 - Present

Design and build cloud computing architectures that customers depend on to operate flexible and agile.

Create cloud solutions to meet and exceed customer requirements.

Translating the project's specific needs into a cloud framework that will address those needs and considering the project's needs in terms of resource usage and scalability.

Design the cloud environment, ensuring it meets all customer requirements. Perform deployment, maintenance, monitoring and management tasks within this implemented cloud framework and oversee cloud security.

Completing the integration of new applications into the cloud environment. Provide training and guidance to all those whose roles put them in touch with the cloud

Track cloud space usage and ensure the structure is operating at full efficiency. Work to understand customer needs and implement cloud strategies designed to address those needs.

Migrate, when necessary, to bring tools and other elements to the cloud.

SENIOR INFRASTRUCTURE ANALYST

Solo Network, Oct 2019 - Mar 2021

Provide remote, reactive, and proactive troubleshooting support in Microsoft environments such as: Failover Clustering, Remote Desktop Services (RDS, App-V, UE-V, MED-V), Windows Client / Server Deployment (WDS, MDT), Active Directory, SCCM, Azure, etc ... Implement projects in these same environments, providing the end customer with a robust and reliable work environment.

MICROSOFT SUPPORT ENGINEER

Wipro, Jun 2015 - Oct 2019

Provide remote, reactive, and proactive troubleshooting support for Microsoft clients in the following areas: Failover Cluster, Backup, Bitlocker, Microsoft Product Activation Service (Volume License, Microsoft 365) Remote Desktop Services (RDS, App-V, Windows Client/Server (WDS, MDT), as well as support for technologies such as: Active Directory, Network Services (DNS, DHCP, VPN ...) Accompany the launch of new products and study them, in order to provide the best customer support.

EDUCATION

UNIARA - UNIVERSITY OF ARARAQUARA

MBA in Information Security Management, 2014 - 2015

CESUFOZ - CENTER OF HIGHER EDUCATION OF FOZ DO IGUAÇU
Technology Computer Network Management, 2009 - 2011

CERTIFICATION

- Microsoft Certified Solutions Expert (MCSE): Core Infrastructure
- Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate (MCSA): Windows Server 2012
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Administrator Associate
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Architect Solutions Expert
- Microsoft Certified: Azure DevOps Engineer Expert
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Virtual Desktop Specialty
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Stack Hub Operator Associate
- Google Cloud Platform Associate Cloud Engineer
- Google Cloud Platform Professional Cloud Architect